Ron Li

Fourth year Business Administration and Computer Science student at the University of Waterloo and Wilfrid Laurier University. Working experience with OO programing using C++, C# and Java as well as web development using Angular at Manulife. Additional work experience with SQL and backend database management at Polaris Transportation. Quick learner, analytical and strong problem solving and communication skills from participation in many hackathons.

Personal Info

Phone:

519-591-0551

Email:

rl5li@edu.uwaterloo.ca

GitHub:

https://github.com/RunEMC

LinkedIn:

http://ca.linkedin.com/in/ronli1

Languages

English	Fluent
French	Proficient
Mandarin	Fluent

A Key Skills

Team Work Communication **Creative Thinking Problem Solving** Quick Learner

■ Technical Skills

Languages	<u>Tools</u>
Java/C++/C#	VBA
HTML/CSS/JS	Git
SQL/PHP	MS Office
Python	Bash
C	VIM

Hobbies and Interests

Holds a senior executive position at the University of Waterloo badminton club.

Loves to experiment with new tech ideas and thinking of new ways to build something cool with them.

Interested in AI/machine learning and mobile platforms.

Work Experience

January 2018 -April 2018

Software Developer/Project Coordinator

Manulife Financial / Toronto, Ontario

- Performed back-end service migration from SOAP to POST in .NET using C#.
- Developed a technology radar from Ad Hoc MVPs to a final production build using Angular, Spring, Flyway and Gradle.
- Implemented macro enhancements for report generation in VBA.

January 2017 -April 2017

Data Analyst

Polaris Transportation Group / Mississauga, Ontario

- Increased work efficiency by writing scripts for accessing the database with SQL queries.
- Identified key sources of profitability from analyzing important points of interest in the retrieved data.



Education

September 2015 -Present

Bachelors of Computer Science

University of Waterloo

Completed courses in OO programming, algorithms, data structures, compilers, OS, stats and optimization.

September 2015 -Present

Bachelors of Business Administration

Wilfrid Laurier University

Semi-finalist in the Blackberry BBM business case competition.

Additional Experience

September 2018

Winner of Ubisoft's Hackers Nest API Prize at Hack the North 2018

University of Waterloo

- Built a C++ application using Ubisoft's custom game engine.
- Abstracted collision detection and event handling to support desired game features.

February 2018

Top 5 Hacks at QHacks 2018

Queen's University

- Built a web app that scrapes Twitter pages for victims at risk of self harm.
- Integrated STDlib's functions libraries and IBM Watson's Sentiment Analysis API.

November 2017

Top 6 Hacks at Hack Western 4

University of Western Ontario

- Built an A/R, image recognition Android/IOS app.
- Won the prize for Best Use of IBM Watson Visual API.
- Won Best Hack for Social Impact sponsored by Sun Life.